Naval Saini

I have been working with corporate and in startups since 2006, and with remote teams since 2017. I have bootstrapped in the past and built small teams at my own startup. The engineers who started their careers with me are doing great in life now. My impact has been churning code, involving proactively in product discussions, chasing KPIs and getting MVPs faster to the market.

India **(+91) 9560375909** navalnovel@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/navalsaini

EXPERIENCE

Bitfinex.com, Remote — Consultant, Sr. Frontend Engineer

Since July 2021

(reactis

I currently work at Bitfinex (a popular crypto exchange) in their frontend team. I have worked on several of their products – the trading application, tether gold, merchant payment gateways and now on a p2p crypto exchange platform.

Lantern.so, Paris/Remote — Consultant, Full-Stack

Since April 2020

(reactis, nodejs, python)

I was a founding engineer at a <u>Y-combinator startup</u> in the space of automated analytics insights generation. I also implemented a few analytics insights in python, in addition to the usual JS full-stack development.

HalfChess Game, a personal project — *React-Native*

Active since 2016

(react-native, nodejs, mongodb, google cloud)

<u>Halfchess</u> is a novel game for improving chess skills and works on Android, iOS and web. It has been <u>covered in startup media (YourStory)</u>. This also reached the top 12th place in the <u>Pioneer</u> competition globally.

Smart-Reporting.com, Munich/Remote — *Consultant*, *ReactJs*

July 2019 - Dec 2019

(reactjs)

I worked remotely as a frontend engineer of a Healthcare app used by radiologists.

McKinsey and Co, Poland — Senior Engineer, ReactJs

Nov 2017 - Jan 2019

(reactis, nodeis)

I worked remotely on an Analytical tool for the energy industry, to be used internally in McKinsey by its analysts and consultants for forecasting.

INDUSTRIES

My interest lies in blockchains, consumer tech, and solving the next billion problems.

TECHNOLOGY

Reactjs, React native, Node.js, Python, Solidity

MANAGEMENT

Product and Growth Teams, Planning and estimation, Agile, Hiring, Induction, Performance management.

TALKS

Modular services in Nodejs monolith, JSFOO, Bangalore, 2017

My experiments with Chess,

London node users group, 2018

SIDE-PROJECTS

Automated Trading with iPython.

Halfchess is a chess variation

<u>rewq</u> is a tool for making URL shortcuts

JioMoney Reliance, Bangalore (India) — Consultant

Nov 2015 - July 2016

(nodejs, calabash automated testing)

<u>JioMoney</u> is a mobile digital wallet. I worked on a ticket booking platform, a bus aggregator and a payment wallet backend.

Flipflop app, Delhi — Founder

2010 - 2015

As a founder, I had built and mentored a young **team of 5 engineers**. Our projects are listed in a <u>gist (click here)</u>.

Qualcomm, Hyderabad — Customer Engineer

Feb 2009 - July 2010

In <u>Qualcomm</u>, I worked on customer issues related to android audio multimedia and stability.

Conexant/NXP, Delhi — BSP Engineer

July 2006 - Feb 2009

I worked on open source tools and technologies (mainly linux kernel) in embedded systems. I submitted a memory management patch to the Linux kernel community, "O_DIRECT patch for processors with VIPT cache for mainline kernel".

BOOTCAMPS

Solidity Bootcamp, Eth Denver

Nov - Dec, 2022

A 5 week bootcamp for handson solidity development.

GROWTHX.CLUB, Product & Growth Program

Feb - April, 2021

An 8 week online program that teaches about scaling product growth.

EDUCATION

SIT, **GGSIPU**, Delhi — Master of Computer Applications

July 2003 - July 2006

Delhi University, Delhi — Bachelor of Computer Applications

July 1999 - July 2003

OPEN-SOURCE

<u>5 Npm modules</u> used in personal projects

<u>Archiejs</u> modular backend development

<u>Github account</u> all repos are created by me or have some contribution

RESEARCH

Filed for patent in 2013, A system and method for delivering curated and relevant assets to end users

PAPERS

I wrote 3 independent unpublished papers in my academic years and have worked on several computer projects since I was 13.

https://independent.academia.edu/NavalSaini